<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ataylor.io</title>
    <link>https://ataylor.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on ataylor.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 01:04:26 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ataylor.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Publicizing thoughts</title>
      <link>https://ataylor.io/blog/first/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 01:04:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ataylor.io/blog/first/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Peering into my soul&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electric Powered Off-Road Vehicle</title>
      <link>https://ataylor.io/proj/gokart/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 23:12:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ataylor.io/proj/gokart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hand-fabricated a full-suspension metal frame from raw of steel tubing. Designed the electronics system for the power train, used CAD software to design the motor and control board mounts and drivetrain assembly and create custom fabricated parts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Replicated hosting within a P2P marketplace</title>
      <link>https://ataylor.io/proj/p2pmkt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 23:11:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ataylor.io/proj/p2pmkt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Created a fork of the OpenBazaar decentralized marketplace project in its early stages to emulate a hosted site environment within a P2P network. Used the Entangled implementation of a Kademlia distributed hash table to facilitate replicated storage of a user’s site across multiple peers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://ataylor.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 22:59:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ataylor.io/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a full-stack developer with a track record of delivering on ambitious projects in both a professional and academic setting. As a cofounder of Peck, I lead a team of developers in the development of a mobile application and web service. I aspire to maintain a holistic vision for a product while managing and participating in the development process. I have experience with a wide variety of technologies that provide me with a strong basis for designing and developing computer systems. I have studied Computer Science at Williams College and the Aquincum Institute of Technology, and am currently taking time off from school to work on a startup in Boston.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compiling Interpreter for x86 written in ARM</title>
      <link>https://ataylor.io/proj/x86toarm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 22:57:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ataylor.io/proj/x86toarm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Created the fastest assembly language interpreter in my Computer Architecture class for large programs by compiling instructions read commands of the x86 instruction set into mappes sequences of ARM instructions which allowed loops to be executed much faster than if they had to be interpreted every time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>