<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Aaron Taylor</title>
    <link>https://ataylor.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Aaron Taylor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Aaron Taylor 2015-{year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2015 18:14:20 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ataylor.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Improvements in Go 1.5</title>
      <link>https://ataylor.io/blog/go15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2015 18:14:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ataylor.io/blog/go15/</guid>
      <description>With the relatively recent release Go 1.5, there are a variety of interesting areas to look at in regards to what&amp;rsquo;s changed with the language. As one would expect based on both Go&amp;rsquo;s philosophy and it&amp;rsquo;s future compatibility guidelines, not much has changed from a language feature standpoint. Still, there a number of exciting under-the-hood enhancements in the latest release.
Package system New functionality has been introduced to the packaging system in two ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linking Dynamic C&#43;&#43; Libraries with Go</title>
      <link>https://ataylor.io/blog/cgolinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2015 22:23:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ataylor.io/blog/cgolinking/</guid>
      <description>These days, I spend a lot of time working with, designing, and implementing APIs. Since Meta is a microservices based application, the contracts that those APIs provide are crucial to designing the interactions with them. Quickly, maintaining good documentation and client libraries becomes nearly as important of a part of the applications as the code itself. Each step forward in functionality must provide solid footing to keep on building.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Website</title>
      <link>https://ataylor.io/blog/blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 01:04:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ataylor.io/blog/blogging/</guid>
      <description>My previous site was written completely from scratch. It gave me a valuable understanding of web fundamentals, but as my time grows short, I needed something with a little more tooling built in. Still, I wanted tools that I could understand. After working extensively with Go in my work at Meta, I felt I had a good enough understanding of its templating system to commit to using it as a the building blocks for my own website.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>